ILGWU. General Executive Board. Appeal Committee cases 5780/018
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. General Executive Board Appeal Committee cases
1926-1983.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. General Executive Board. Appeal Committee
5780/018
7.78 cubic feet
7 linear feet
Correspondence, memoranda, notes.
Contains correspondence and case files of the Grievance Committee, Appeal Committee, Special Investigation Committee, and Election and Objection Committee of the General Executive Board.
5489116
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff
Date completed:
March 2011
EAD encoding:
Cheryl Beredo, March 2011
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was founded in New York City in 1900 by mostly Socialist immigrant workers who sought to unite the various crafts in the growing women's garment industry. The union soon reflected changes in the sector and rapidly organized thousands of unskilled and semi-skilled women, mostly Jewish and Italian young immigrants. Exemplifying the "new unionism," the ILGWU led two of the most widespread and best-known industrial strikes of the early Twentieth Century: the shirtwaist makers' strike of 1909 in New York City and the cloak makers' strike of 1910 in Chicago. The union also tried to adapt to the fragmented and unstable nature of the industry. It adopted the "protocol of peace," a system of industrial relations that attempted to ensure stability and limit strikes and production disruption by providing for an arbitration system to resolve disputes.
The ILGWU exemplified the European-style social unionism of its founding members. They pursued bread and butter issues but provided educational opportunities, benefits, and social programs to union members as well. In 1919, the ILGWU became the first American union to negotiate an unemployment compensation fund that was contributed to by its employers. The ILGWU also pioneered in the establishment of an extremely progressive health care program for its members which included not only regional Union Health Centers but also a resort for union workers, known as Unity House. The Union also had an imaginative and pioneering Education Department which not only trained workers in traditional union techniques, but provided courses in citizenship and the English language.
David Dubinsky, an immigrant from Belarus who came to the US in 1911, provided strong leadership that led to unprecedented growth in the union during his presidency from 1932 to 1966. He led the union through successful internal anti-communist struggles, built on the ascendancy of industrial unionism by encouraging the formation of the Committee for Industrial Organization, and helped the union become an important political force in New York City and state politics, and in the national Democratic Party and Liberal Party as well.
In the period following the Second World War, the union suffered a decline in membership as manufacturers avoided unionization and took advantage of less expensive labor by moving shops from the urban centers in the northeast to the south, and later abroad. The ethnic and racial character of the ILGWU also changed as European immigrants were supplanted by Asians, Latin Americans, African- Americans, and immigrants from the Caribbean.
In July 1995 the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) at a joint convention, forming UNITE (Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees). At the time the new union had a membership of about 250,000 in the United States, Canada, and Puerto Rico.
Conditions Governing Access
The ILGWU Records, except for publications and materials produced for publication, are restricted. Materials created prior to twenty years from the current date are open to researchers only with prior written permission from the Director of the Kheel Center; materials created during the past twenty-years are closed; the minutes of the General Executive Board are closed. For more information contact the Kheel Center.
Related Materials
5780. ILGWU Records
5780/016.ILGWU. General Executive Board minutes
5780/016mf. ILGWU. General Executive Board minutes. Microfilm
5780/189. ILGWU. Perry Parker papers
General
"Permanent deposit"
Women's clothing industry -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Clothing workers -- United States; Industrial relations -- United States; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 22 (New York, N.Y.)
5489116
- Grievance Committee. Correspondence., 1926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases., 1927 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases., 1930 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Grievance and Appeal Committees. Correspondence., 1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases., 1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases., 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Grievance and Appeal Committees. Correspondence & Cases. [folder 1 of 3], 1931 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Grievance and Appeal Committees. Correspondence & Cases. [folder 2 of 3], 1931 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Grievance and Appeal Committees. Correspondence & Cases. [folder 3 of 3], 1931 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases. [folder 1 of 4], 1932 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases. [folder 2 of 2], 1932 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases. [folder 3 of 4], 1932 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases. [folder 4 of 4], 1932 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases., 1933 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases. [folder 1 of 4], 1934 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases. [folder 2 of 4], 1934 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases. [folder 3 of 4], 1934 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases. [folder 4 of 4], 1934 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Special Investigations and Appeal Committees. Minutes, Correspondence & Cases., 1935 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases. [folder 1 of 4], 1935 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases. [folder 2 of 4], 1935 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases. [folder 3 of 4], 1935 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases. [folder 4 of 4], 1935 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Grievance and Appeal Committees. Correspondence, Minutes & Petitions., 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases. [folder 1 of 2], 1935-1936 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases. [folder 2 of 2], 1935-1936 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases. [folder 1 of 2], 1936 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases. [folder 2 of 2], 1936 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Trial and Appeal Committees. Correspondence & Meeting Minutes., 1935-1936 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence., 1935-1937 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence., 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence, Cases and Cutter Committee Notices., 1934-1937 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Appeal Committee. Cases., 1937 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence., 1937 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and General Election Ballots., 1937 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Razimowitz, Joseph. Case of Appeal, Proceeding Minutes and Notes, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases., 1938-1939 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases., 1940 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases., 1941-1943 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence, Cases and Minutes., 1944 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases., 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases., 1940-1944 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases. [folder 1 of 2], 1944 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases. [folder 2 of 2], 1944 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Appeal Committee. Cases, Reports and Misc. Correspondence., 1945 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases., 1943-1945 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Mencoff-Pine Correspondence and Case of Appeal., 1945 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Ames et al. v. Dubinsky. Case of Appeal and Notes., 1945 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases., 1944-1946 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases., 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Appeal Committee. Executive Session Cases and Reports., 1944-1947 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Appeal Committee. Rea, Luigi v. Levine, Feigel., 1947 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Appeal Committee. Minutes and Collection Records., 1947 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases., 1947-1948 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases., 1937-1948 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases., 1948 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence, Cases and Notices. [folder 1 of 2], 1949 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence, Cases and Notices. [folder 2 of 2], 1949 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Appeal Committee. Cohen and Spitzer v. Goretsky et al. Cases & Materials., 1947 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Grievance and Appeal Committees. Correspondence., 1948-1950 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence, Cases and Supplemental Notes., 1951-1952 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence, Minutes and Notices., 1951-1953 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence, Reports and Decisions., 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases., 1952-1954 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases. [folder 1 of 3], 1954 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases. [folder 2 of 3], 1954 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases. [folder 3 of 3], 1954 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence and Cases., 1955-1956 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Election and Objection Committee. Protest-Appeal of Harry Shaw in Connection with 1971 Elections. (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Election and Objection Committee. Protest-Appeal of John Kurtz., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Election and Objection Committee. Miscellaneous Correspondence., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Election and Objection Committee. Procedures for Hearings on Appeal., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Election and Objection Committee. Procedures., 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Election and Objection Committee. Campaign Literature & Correspondence., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Election and Objection Committee. Charges no.1 & 2., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Election and Objection Committee. Charge no.3., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Election and Objection Committee. Charge no.4., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Election and Objection Committee. Charge no.5 & 12., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Election and Objection Committee. Charges no.6,7,8, & 9., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Election and Objection Committee. Charge no.10 & 11., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Election and Objection Committee. Charge no.13., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Election and Objection Committee. Charge no.14., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Election and Objection Committee. Charge no.15., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Election and Objection Committee. Charge no.16., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Election and Objection Committee. Charge no.17., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Election and Objection Committee. Charge no.18., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Election and Objection Committee. Charge no.19., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Election and Objection Committee. Charge no.20., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Election and Objection Committee. Charge no.21., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 21)
- Election and Objection Committee. Charge no.22., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 22)
- Election and Objection Committee. Charge no.23., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 23)
- Election and Objection Committee. Charge no.24., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 24)
- Election and Objection Committee. Violations by United Cutters Welfare League., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 25)
- Election and Objection Committee. Nomination & Election Meetings., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 26)
- Election and Objection Committee. Agenda & Hearings., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 27)
- Election and Objection Committee. Local 10 Appeal to Executive Board., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 28)
- Appeal Committee. Correspondence, Reports and Decision., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 29)
- Appeals Committee. Spitzer, David., 1983 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Appeal Committee. Decisions from 4/12/83, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Appeal Committee. Minutes. Re: Spitzer, David., 1983 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Appeal Committee. Transcript of Election and Objection Committee Hearing Re: Spitzer, David., 1983 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Appeal Committee. Hearing of David Spitzer., 1979 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Appeal Committee. Documents Examined in Spitzer v. Grossman and Leone. [folder 1 of 2], 1981 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Appeal Committee. Documents Examined in Spitzer v. Grossman and Leone. [folder 2 of 2], 1981 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Special Committee. Hearing of David Spitzer. [10/9/80], 1980 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Special Committee. Hearing of David Spitzer. [11/19/80] (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Special Committee. Exhibits Entered into Evidence by Gerald Grossman., 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Special Committee. Exhibits Entered into Evidence by David Spitzer., 1980 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Special Committee. Communications Entered into Evidence by Chairman Herb Kobrin., 1980 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Special Committee. To: ILGWU Executive Board Conferees., 1980 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- General Executive Board. Appeal Committee. In the Matter of Harold C. Leifman and Local 10., 1983 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- General Executive Board. Appeal Committee. In the Matter of Willy Lelong and Local 205 Elections., 1983 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- General Executive Board. Appeal Committee. In the Matter of Local 424 Alice Marker, Charlotte Darlene Cover, Twila Bowser and Doris Balestrini., 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- General Executive Board. Appeal Committee. In the Matter of Leslie Spillet., 1983 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- General Executive Board. Appeal Committee. David Spitzer v. Gerald Grossman and Richard Leone. [folder 1 of 2], 1981 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- General Executive Board. Appeal Committee. David Spitzer v. Gerald Grossman and Richard Leone. [folder 2 of 2], 1981 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- General Executive Board. Appeal Committee. Hearing in the Matter of David Spitzer v. Local 10. [folder 1 of 5], 1979 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- General Executive Board. Appeal Committee. Hearing in the Matter of David Spitzer v. Local 10. [folder 2 of 5], 1979 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- General Executive Board. Appeal Committee. Hearing in the Matter of David Spitzer v. Local 10. [folder 3 of 5], 1979 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- General Executive Board. Appeal Committee. Hearing in the Matter of David Spitzer v. Local 10. [folder 4 of 5], 1979 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- General Executive Board. Appeal Committee. Hearing in the Matter of David Spitzer v. Local 10. [folder 5 of 5], 1979 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- General Executive Board. Appeal Committee. Meeting Draft., 1980 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- General Executive Board. Appeal Committee. Summary File for Appeal of David Spitzer. [folder 1 of 3], 1979-1980 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- General Executive Board. Appeal Committee. Summary File for Appeal of David Spitzer. [folder 2 of 3], 1979-1980 (Box 13, Folder 14)
- General Executive Board. Appeal Committee. Summary File for Appeal of David Spitzer. [folder 3 of 3], 1979-1980 (Box 13, Folder 15)
- General Executive Board. Appeal Committee. In the Matter of Leslie Spillet. Audio., 1983 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  Scope and Contents
  7 audio cassettes. Cassettes 1-3 and 5-8.